let quiz=[
    {
      question: "The earliest experiments on chromosome theory and inheritance were developed by :",
      option: [
           "Gregor Mendel",
           "Jonas Salk",
           "Charles Sternak",
           "Robert Oppenheimer",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "As of August 1991, how many DIFFERENT women have won Nobel Prizes in the scientific fields of physics, chemistry, and physiology or medicine? Is it :",
      option: [
           "2",
           "5",
           "9",
           "12",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Most commercial nuclear plants worldwide are cooled by :",
      option: [
           "sodium",
           "mercury",
           "helium",
           "water",
      ],
       answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Radioisotopes which are used in medical diagnosis are known as :",
      option: [
           "tracers",
           "silver bullets",
           "markers",
           "dyes",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "The largest breeder reactor built to date is located where :",
      option: [
           "USSR",
           "Japan",
           "France",
           "United States",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "The radioactive element most commonly detected in humans is :",
      option: [
           "potassium-40",
           "cobalt-60",
           "iodine-131",
           "plutonium-238",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Name the english naturalist who, while credited with being the codeveloper of the theory of evolution by natural selection, is much less famous for this than his codeveloper :",
      option: [
           "Erasmus Darwin",
           "Robert Ludlow",
           "Alfred Russel Wallace",
           "Rudolf Virchow",
      ],
      answer: 3
    },
    {
      question: "Atolls are most probably formed by :",
      option: [
           "a rise in the earth's crust",
           "sand brought in from the mainland",
           "collapse of the center of a volcano",
           "coralk reef upbuilding during subsidence",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Glaucoma is treated by which of the following :",
      option: [
           "androgenic drug",
           "androgenic blocking drug",
           "cholinergic drug",
           "anticholinergic drug",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "Pollination by wind is called :",
      option: [
           "Autogamy",
           "Entomophily",
           "Anemophily",
           "Ornithophily",
      ],
      answer:3,
    },
    {
  question: "What are the three elements of a Bipolar Transistor?",
  option: [
  "grid, plate, cathode",
  "Suppressor, deflector, target",
  "energizer, controller, terminus",
  "emitter, base, collector",
  ],
  answer: 4, 
},
{
  question: "To reverse the direction of rotation of a three phase AC induction motor , do one of the following :",
  option: [
  "reverse any two of the three phase connections",
  "change the frequency of the applied AC power",
  "operate the motor below the stall torque at very high slip",
  "None of the above",
  ],
  answer: 1, 
},
{
  question: "In a certain elctronic circuit the ouput is positive  if input 1 is positive and input 2 is 0 . if both inputs are positive the output is 0. This is :",
  option: [
  "an AND circuit",
  "a NOR circuit",
  "an OR circuit ",
  "a high pass filter",
  ],
  answer: 3, 
},
{
  question: "In a typical power plant used to generate electricity in the U.S. , the % of energy in the fuel i.e. converted to electricity is about:",
  option: [
  "99 %",
  "50 %",
  "35 %",
  "10 %",
  ],
  answer: 3, 
},
{
  question: "Electric power is less expensive at night because:",
  option: [
  "more hydroelectric generation is brought on line at night",
  "there is less demand at night",
  "pollution control is less stringent at night ",
  "power plants are more efficient",
  ],
  answer: 2, 
},
    ]
